It looks like the power consumption
in this tower is mostly concentrated....
このタワー内で特に電力消費が激しいのは…２カ所ですね
in two areas.
The top floor and the basement.
最上階付近と地下
I wonder which one has what we're looking for.
どっちが本命かな
There's a radio tower on the rooftop,
屋上近辺は電波塔ですからね
so the large power consumption there is to be expected.
そりゃ大量の電力消費も当然ですよ
However, it seems details on the facilities
below are unavailable, even from this terminal.
ところが下の施設はここからでさえ詳細が掴めない
The map here only covers down to the fourth level of the basement.
案内表示では地下４階までしかないようだが…
However, as you might recall, the early
blueprints showed the basement as having twenty floors.
それがね　設計当初の図面だと 地下２０階まであるんですよ
Something's definitely up.
こいつはうさんくさい
Hm?
What's the matter?
どうした
A vehicle from the Bureau is already on its way here.
もうこっちに公安局の車が向かってます
Kougami Shinya, of course.
きっと狡噛慎也だろう 驚かないよ
That doesn't surprise me.
Let's split up.
二手に分かれよう
I'll go upstairs. You go downstairs.
僕は上　君は下だ
Are you sure? From what we know, it's bound to be in the basement.
いいんですか
この場合本命は…
Kougami will come after me.
狡噛は僕を狙ってくるだろう
Therefore, it makes more sense if I draw him away.
なら　陽動を引き受けるのが合理的だ
Choe Gu-Sung, I have high expectations for you.
チェ·グソン 君の働きに期待してるよ
Understood. Please leave it to me.
分かりました　お任せを
Well, then. It would seem that this
party is finally approaching its conclusion.
さて　パーティーもいよいよ大詰めか
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear, lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
#16: The Gate to Judgment
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:叶子 西西   校对:西西   时间轴:葛蔓 压制：娜夏
Bingo. Makishima Shougo!
当たりだ　槙島聖護
What are you after in the Ministry of Welfare's Nona Tower?
厚生省ノナタワーに何が目的だ
The communications terminal has been cut off!
通報装置が遮断されています
Hey, Shion.
おい　志恩
How's it going over there?
そっちはどう
This place is about to become a war zone.
これから修羅場だ
Is it possible to check the Nona Tower's
security cameras from the Public Safety Bureau?
公安局からノナタワーの監視カメラをチェックできるか
The Ministry of Welfare is a high-ranking organization, you know.
厚生省は一応上位組織なのよ
So you can't do it?
できないのか
If it's okay to use the back door, I can do it,
裏口使っていいならできるけど
but I don't want to be held responsible for this later.
後で責任問題とかになったりしたらヤダな
Understood.
分かりました
I'll take full responsibility.
責任は全て私が取ります
Got that on tape.
今の言葉記録しちゃったもんね
Okay. I'll use the key to the back door.
ＯＫ  裏口の鍵を使っちゃいましょう
The next thing we have to do is call Gino, Inspector.
次はギノに連絡だ　監視官
So you're absolutely sure?
間違いないんだな
Shion's currently tracking them to confirm whether it's Makishima.
槙島かどうかは現在志恩さんが追跡中ですが
But we know for sure that an armed
group has broken into the Nona Tower.
ノナタワーに武装集団が侵入したことは疑いようのない事実です
The Tower has been compromised and its
electronics and communications systems have been isolated.
タワーは攻撃を受け 電子的通信的にも孤立しています
Considering that they broke straight in through the front entrance,
エントランスを突破した状況を見ても
it's clear that the security system can't handle this kind of intrusion.
ここの警備システムではしのぎきれません
Understood, Inspector Tsunemori.
分かった…
常守監視官 あと聞こえてるか　狡噛と縢
Also, can you hear me, Kougami, Kagari?
Yep.
へーい
The riots are still in full force, so we of
Division 1 will deal with the incident at the Tower.
暴動はまだ続いている以上 タワーの方は俺たち一係で対応する
Now, listen.
いいか もしも本当に槙島がいたら…
If Makishima is really there...
Capture Makishima Shougo.
「槙島聖護の身柄を確保しろ」
Apprehend him.
逮捕しろ
We need to interrogate him.
尋問の必要がある
Make sure you capture him alive.
必ず生きたまま捕まえるんだ
I'll try.
努力してみる
Trying's not good enough!
努力するのは当然だろ
I need you to do it!
重要なのは結果だ
What's the matter?
どうしました
Well... Nothing, really.
いや…ちょっとな
Should we wait for Gino and the others to arrive?
ギノさんたちの到着待ちます
That's not funny.
冗談よせよ
Yeah, I guess not.
ですよね
But this tower is too big for the three of us to investigate alone.
でも　このタワーは３人で探索するには大き過ぎる
It'll be fine.
大丈夫　俺たちにはすご腕の分析官が付いてる
We've got an expert at information analysis.
Yeah, the very best there is.
情報分析の女神さまが
Hey, are you boys talking about me?
ねぇねぇそれって私のことでしょ
We might be. How's it going?
そうかもな…
I'm accessing all of Nona Tower's security cameras from the lab here at the Bureau.
首尾は
ノナタワーの全監視カメラを公安局ラボで制御中
The enemy has split into two groups.
敵は現在二手に分かれてる
Four men upstairs, four downstairs.
上に４人　下に４人
Where's Makishima?
He's upstairs.
槙島は
He just got off the elevator at the top floor.
上　さっき最上階のエレベーターを降りたところ
Makishima Shougo
The top floor?
最上階　官庁フロアではなく
Not the government office floor?
Right. They went straight to the antenna block.
ええ アンテナ区画に直行よ
I wonder if they're trying to hijack the radio signal or something.
電波ジャックでもしようってのかしら
Their target isn't the Ministry of Welfare?
標的は厚生省じゃ…ない
So who headed downstairs?
下に向かったのはどんな連中だ
I'm not sure. They went down to the
fourth level of the basement, then disappeared.
それが…
地下４階まで降りたところで行方が分からないのよね
I wonder if they went through the maintenance hatch and entered a utility tunnel or something.
そっからメンテナンスハッチくぐって共同溝にでも入ったのかな
What the heck? That seems fishy.
何それ 気になるね
Let's go, Inspector.
行くぞ監視官 槙島を追う
We'll follow Makishima.
But what about downstairs?
でも下は
I'll go.
俺が行くよ
But then it'll be one versus four.
だけどそれじゃ１対４に…
It'll still be two versus four for you guys, right?
そっちだって２対４っしょ
And since Makishima's there,
wouldn't upstairs be more dangerous?
むしろ槙島がいる分 上の方がヤバいんじゃないの
Okay!
分かりました
Kagari!
Hm?
縢
Don't do anything reckless!
無茶だけはすんな
I don't need you to tell me that, Ko!
コウちゃんにだけは言われたかねえよ
Analyst, can we use this elevator?
分析官 このエレベーター使えるか
No. It's locked down.
ロックが掛けられてて使えない
I can't unlock it from here, either.
ラボからじゃ解除は無理
Dammit!
What about the stairs?
クソッ
階段は
They're on the 90th floor!
敵は地上９０階よ
Hold on a sec.
ちょっと待ってなさい
There it is!
見つけた
The service elevators that transport Drones
ドローン運搬に使う業務用特殊エレベーターの制御は
run on a separate system than those at the Tower's center.
タワー中央とは別系統
They're still operational!
現在も稼働中
Can you give us directions?
ルートをナビしてくれ
Okay!
ＯＫ
Turn right at the hallway ahead.
その先の通路を右…
That's where I lost track of them on the security camera videos.
監視カメラの映像で追跡できたのはそこまでよ
What's there?
何があるわけ
Well... According to the blueprints, it's just a dead end.
それが…図面だとただの行き止まり
It might be some sort of trap. Be careful.
何かのワナかもしれない 気を付けて
Yeah, yeah.
へい へい
What's that?
何あれ
Shion, the basement should only have four floors, right?
先生　この地下フロアって４階で終わりのはずだよね
That's how it's supposed to be.
そのはずなんだけど…
I don't like this. This really isn't my kind of scene.
嫌だな
俺　こういうの柄じゃねえのに
I really don't like this.
やめてくれよ
Shinya.
慎也君
This should go without saying,
まさかとは思うけど
but don't even think about using
the EMP grenades near the radio tower.
ノナタワーのアンテナ塔で磁パルスグレネードを使おうなんて
If I did, Gino would kill me himself.
思わないでよね
後でギノに殺されるからな
So how are you gonna deal with those helmets they're wearing?
じゃあ　敵のヘルメット対策　どうするつもり
Since Akane's with you, you can't use your Dominators.
朱ちゃんが一緒だとドミネーターを封じられるわよ
That's why I picked one of them up and brought it with me.
そのために わざわざ１個拾ってきたんだ
When someone's wearing this,
their Crime Coefficient can't be read.
こいつをかぶったやつの犯罪係数は 外部から読み取れなくなる
In other words, if Inspector Tsunemori wears this,
つまり　常守監視官がこいつをかぶれば
they won't be able to copy her Psycho-Pass to their own helmets.
敵のヘルメットにサイコパスをコピーされることもない
I see.
なるほどね
Putting that aside, though...
それにしても…
What on Earth could Makishima be after?
槙島の目的はいったい…
Makishima is a decoy.
槙島はおとりだ
The one who'll do the job is probably headed to the basement.
たぶん本命は下に向かっている
Otherwise, it wouldn't make much sense for them to have split up.
そう考えなきゃ　この状況で敵が二手に分かれた説明がつかない
There's a mysterious facility that doesn't
even have security cameras in the basement, right?
地下に監視カメラもない よく分からない施設があるんだよな
Yeah, but I haven't heard a thing from Shu since he went down there,
そうなんだけど…
秀君からの連絡も途絶えちゃってて
so I have no idea what's going on.
何がどうなってるのやら…
Makishima and the others must have
some idea of what this facility really is.
その施設の正体が槙島たちには何となくつかめているはずだ
Then... why...
じゃあ　何で…
Our priority isn't to stop him from
achieving his goal, but to drive him into a corner.
槙島の目的を阻止することよりも
槙島本人を追い詰める方が優先だ
Right?
そうだろ
Shion, I'm telling you, this place is seriously bad news.
なあ先生 ここ絶対ヤバいって
I wanna get out of here.
俺もう帰りて…
Shion?
Communication error.
先生
「通信エラー」
System link cannot be established.
「システムとのリンクを構築できません」
Hey, this isn't funny!
おいおいおいおい…
You friggin' bastard!
クソ野郎が
How's it going there?
そっちはどうだ 仕留めたか
Did you kill him?
Sorry. Your friend met an unfortunate accident.
残念　返り討ちだぜ
Oh, really?
おやおや…
Not bad.
やるもんだね
You're an Enforcer from the Bureau, right?
公安局の執行官だろ
Who are you?
何者だあんた
Why don't we have a little talk?
ちょっと話をしないか
This entire basement is designed to block electromagnetic radiation.
この地下は大規模な電波暗室になっててね
Only those of us who are inside can communicate with each other.
中にいる俺たちしか通信はできないようになっている
Your Dominator doesn't work either, does it?
ドミネーターも使えなくなってるだろ
Even if you had an Inspector there with you,
you wouldn't have to worry about being shot.
今そこに監視官がいても撃たれる心配はない
No matter what you said or did,
they couldn't do anything to stop you.
何を喋り何を遣らかそうとお咎め無し
How does it feel?
どうだい　久しぶりに自由の身になった感想は
To finally have your freedom again?
It's a bit hard to enjoy being free
in this cramped dungeon, you know?
悪くねえわな こんな狭っ苦しい穴蔵じゃなけりゃ
Soon we'll have freedom in the outside world too.
もうじき外の世界でも俺たちは自由になれる
If we destroy the Sibyl System,
シビュラシステムをぶち壊してやれば
this crazy world will be overturned from its very foundations.
このいかれた世界は根本からひっくり返るぜ
Hey, hey, are you serious?
おいおい　正気かあんた
This isn't a joke.
笑い事じゃない
Behind the door that I'm facing
right now is the core of the Sibyl System.
今の俺から扉一つ隔てた向こう側に
シビュラシステムの中枢がある
What?!
You and I are the same.
俺もあんたも同じ潜在犯だ
We're latent criminals.
I live like a rat, sneaking from hole to hole,
俺はネズミみたいにこそこそ隠れて暮らし
and you live like a disposable hunting dog wearing a collar.
あんたは首輪をはめられた使い捨ての猟犬だ
Hey, tell me what you really think.
なあ　本音を聞かせてくれよ
How do you feel when you see
those who took everything away from us,
俺たちから何もかも奪い 虫けらみたいに扱ってきた連中が
those who treated us like scum, killing each other all over town?
今街じゅうで殺し合ってるざまはどうだ
Don't you think it serves them right?
いい気味だと思わないか
Yeah, I completely agree.
ああ　まったく同感だね
To be honest, I was pleased.
正直胸がスッとしたよ
No matter where I went, I was treated like a murderous animal.
いつだってどこだって俺は人殺しのケダモノ扱いだった
But now it's they who are the animals.
それが今じゃやつらの方がよっぽどぶざまなケダモノだ
I wonder what goes through their minds as
they feel their friends' blood splatter all over them.
どんな気分で仲間の返り血を浴びてるのやら
Then...
Don't get me wrong, you slimy bastard!
だったら…
勘違いすんじゃねえよ ゲス野郎が
Sibyl is a load of shit, but you guys reek just as badly.
シビュラもクソだが てめえらもクソだ
Who do you think you are, manipulating others
他人をいいように踊らせて生かすの殺すの
and talking about whether to let them live or die?!
何様のつもりだよ
If Sibyl is God, then who are you supposed to be? The Devil?
シビュラが神様だってんなら てめえらは悪魔にでもなった気分か
Don't make me laugh!
バカ抜かせ
We're just human refuse who can do
nothing but envy the happiness others have.
俺もあんたも他人の幸せがねたましいってだけのごみクズさ
I don't care if thousands of citizens in this damn town end up dying.
このクソったれな街の市民さまどもが何千人と死んでこうがかまやしねえ
But I can't stand the idea of the guys who're
making them kill each other getting off scot-free.
だがな　あいつらに殺し合いをやらせてるやつだけが
のうのうと生きてるってのが気に食わねえんだよ
You should be the first to die!
まずてめえから真っ先に死ねよ
You should die over and over, once for each person you killed!
殺した数だけ繰り返し死んどけってんだよ
You've killed many latent criminals yourself, have you not?
あんただって同じ潜在犯を何人も殺してきたんだろう
Enforcer, how many times will you have to die?
執行官…あんたはいったい何度繰り返して死ねば済むんだい
Well, if I really do end up in Hell the
first time, I'm sure the man in charge can tell me.
まあ　一度死んだ先に地獄ってもんがあるんなら
そこで閻魔さまが教えてくれるんだろうさ
And here I thought we could become friends.
友達になれると思ったんだけどな
My friends are fighting your boss upstairs.
俺のダチは今上であんたのボスとやり合ってるよ
In other words, I won't betray them.
だからこっちも不義理はできねえ
I'll come over and kill you as soon as I can.
今すぐにでもあんたを殺しに行ってやる
Though, if you've got some time to spare,
まあ　その前に間に合うようなら
it'd be nice if you could destroy Sibyl before I get there.
シビュラもぶっ壊してくれると助かるね
That way, the two things I hate most will
disappear from this world at the same time.
俺としちゃ世の中から気に食わないものが２つ同時に消えてなくなるわけだからな
I'll try my best, though the security
on this last door is proving hard to crack.
善処しよう
最後の扉のセキュリティーが難物なんだけど
Makishima is in the very back of the
top floor, by the emergency stairway!
槙島は最上階の一番奥
非常階段の近く
There are no security cameras around there, so I can't help you!
その周辺には監視カメラがないから援護できない
That info is more than enough.
そこまで分かりゃ　上等だよ
Crime Coefficient is 24.
「犯罪係数　２４執行対象ではありません」
Not a target for enforcement action.
What?!
The trigger will be locked.
Inspector?!
監視官
I'm okay.
大丈夫…
But why didn't the Dominator work?
でも　何でドミネーターが…
How careless of me. Makishima's here.
うかつだったぜ ここには槙島がいる
His Psycho-Pass is being copied to their helmets.
やつのサイコパスがこいつらのヘルメットにコピーされているんだ
So I was wearing one for nothing, huh?
ヘルメット　かぶり損でしたね
Once I stop the bleeding, I'll catch up with you.
止血したら後を追います
Please go on ahead!
先に行ってください
But you're...
でもあんたは…
Don't let Makishima get away!
槙島を逃がさないで
That's an order!
これは命令です
Shit!
You fought quite well, considering your wounds.
その傷でよくやるもんだ
You are Kougami Shinya.
お前は狡噛慎也だ
You are Makishima Shougo!
お前は槙島聖護だ
Crime Coefficient is 0.
「犯罪係数　０」
"Justice is subject to dispute; might is easily recognized and is not disputed.
「正義は議論の種になるが 力は非常にはっきりしている」
So we cannot give might to justice."
「そのため　人は正義に力を与えることができなかった」
Sorry, but "I have long since learned, as a measure of elementary hygiene,
悪いな　俺は
「誰かがパスカルを引用したら用心すべきだ」とかなり前に学んでいる
to be on guard when anyone quotes Pascal."
I knew you'd say that.
そうくると思ってたよ
That's Ortega, right?
オルテガだな
If you'd quoted Pascal, I would've said the same words to you.
もしも君がパスカルを引用したら
やっぱり僕も同じ言葉を返しただろう
Finding something we agree on doesn't really make me happy.
貴様と意見が合ったところでうれしくはないな
I'd love to talk the night away with you,
語り明かすのも楽しそうだが
but unfortunately I'm rather preoccupied at the moment.
あいにく今僕は他の用件で忙しい
That's not my problem.
知ったことか
I'll kill you right here, right now.
この場で殺してやる
I'm surprised to hear those words from a detective.
刑事の言葉とは思えない
There's no one else pulling your strings.
お前に黒幕はいない
All the other small-timers are just being manipulated by you.
他の雑魚はお前に操られているだけだ
There'll be time to investigate the
truth behind this case after I kill you.
事件の真相はお前を殺した後でゆっくり調べればいい
You know, the last time we met,
I could've finished you off as you lay dying.
以前会ったとき 死にかけの君にとどめを刺すこともできたんだ
Don't you feel you owe me something for letting you live?
見逃してあげた恩義を感じてくれないのか
Sorry, but you might end up regretting that decision!
せいぜい後悔するこったな
Don't you want to know the truth about the Sibyl System?!
シビュラシステムの正体が知りたくないのか
That can wait!
そんなものは後回しでいいんだよ
I had hoped this would end in a less disappointing manner.
思っていたより拍子抜けの結末だが…
Even so, for the first time in a long while,
I was able to leave my daily tedium behind.
それでも久々に退屈を忘れた
I appreciate it.
感謝してるよ
Kougami!
狡噛さん
Inspector...
監視官…
Kill him.
殺せ…
Makishima Shougo.
槙島聖護…
You're under arrest.
あなたを…逮捕します
What the hell is this?!
何なんだ　こりゃ…
This is the true form of the Sibyl System!
こいつがシビュラシステムの正体だ
We don't even have to destroy this.
この手でぶち壊すまでもねえ
If we make this public, it'll be the end of this country.
こいつを世間に公表すればこの国はおしまいだ
And this time, people will riot for real.
今度こそ本当の暴動が起きる
No one will be able to stop them!
もう誰にも止められねえ
Target's Threat Judgment has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モードリーサル·エリミネーター」
Aim carefully and eliminate the target.
「慎重に照準を定め 対象を排除してください」
Ch-Chief?!
きょ…局長
You're...
あんたは…
Enforcement mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
「執行モード ノンリーサル·パラライザー」
Aim calmly... and bring... the...
「落ち着いて…」
Oh, gimme a break... This bites.
やってらんねえよ　クソが…
There's no way I could love anyone,
Dareka wo aisuru koto nante
Dekiru wake nakutte
But I wish to be loved by someone in turn
The world may not have
Dakedo dareka ni aisaretakute
Ended yesterday after all,
Kawaranai kinou ga zutto tsuzuita to shite mo
But we will not budge
Doko ni mo ike ya shinainda
watashi to kimi
From where we are
Kamisama doko he itte shimatta no nee
God, in favor of which parts have you left us?
Henji wa nakute itsu datte sou da yo
I receive no reply, I never do
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I walk with you
Anata to iku
Donna tsumi mo
I will share all your sins
Seotte ageru
Together with you
Michi naki michi wo
Aruiteku no
I walk
A trackless path
Anata to futari de
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This is a world where the mental state and
personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed,
these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are
commonly called "Psycho-Pass".